# JAMES CAMERON-BURN CV

Senior Software Engineer

Birth Name: James Cockburn

PhD Thesis: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1707.08221 Core Skills: Python, AWS, CI/CD, Docker, SQL, TypeScript Glasgow, Scotland james.cameronburn@icloud.com +44 7595 165202

## **Summary**

I am a self-motivated and passionate software engineer with a wide range of experience in modern software engineering technologies and practices. I have a penchant for learning and for making other people's lives easier through the use of technology.

# **Professional Experience**

## Senior Software Engineer - Wayflyer

July 2022 - present

- · Fully designed and implemented an anonymise-then-clone system for developers to test against representative data
- · Fully designed and implemented a regression test system leveraging that functionality
- · Implemented CLI tooling to allow developers to work on a remote machine whilst remaining within a provided Docker devcontainer
- · Implemented fundamental changes to the signup process to improve user experience and data quality with zero downtime

#### Software Engineer / Software Engineer - Skyscanner

Sep 2017 - July 2022

- · Independently implemented a process for language version migrations, resulting in around 300 services moving from Python 3.6 before it became end of life
- · Introduced CI-time Docker Image acceptance tests to proactively catch regressions
- · Maintained and improved in-house continuous integration and continuous deployment systems
- · Maintained and improved in-house microservice libraries and Docker base images for Python, Java and Node, js

## **Side Projects Experience**

#### Full Stack Software Engineer - New Project

October 2024 - present

- · Currently developing a new web application in the field of finance management
- · Technologies include: Golang, ReactJS with react-router, AWS and AuthO

## Full Stack Software Engineer - Learn with Dr Laura

July 2023 - present

- · Full technical responsibility of a professional tutoring business, learnwithdrlaura.com
- · Fully designed and implemented the site which includes static marketing content and an authenticated user-facing application for lesson management
- · Technologies include: nginx, Vue.js, FastAPI, AWs Route 53, AWS DynamoDB, AWS EC2, AWS SES, AWS Cognito and Python asyncio

#### **Education**

## PhD Student in Theoretical Particle Physics - University of Edinburgh

Aug 2013 - Sep 2017

- · Mathematical calculations of particle collision events within the High Energy Jets (HEJ) framework
- · C++ implementation of numerical integration techniques to solve the equations in the existing HEJ codebase
- · Undergraduate tutoring, with courses covering Quantum Mechanics, Mathematical Physics and Python

#### MSci Theoretical Physics - University College London

Aug 2009 - Aug 2013

- · Graduated with First-Class Honours
- $\cdot$  Embedded Master's project included learning C++ from scratch to rewrite a FORTRAN codebase to perform quantum mechanical calculations
- · Awarded a prize for 'Best use of software in an undergraduate project'